Guide to the WCSU Undergraduate Writing and English Theses RG 6.1.7
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Undergraduate Writing and English Theses
2003-2011
RG 6.1.7
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
3.0 Linear feet 3 boxes
This is a collection of undergraduate student papers. Some undergraduate courses require a final paper or thesis in lieu of a final exam.
Western Connecticut State University.
Provenance
Transferred from John Briggs on the WCSU Writing Department in the Summer of 2010.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Student projects; Theses.
- 2003
  - Moran, David Easy money, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    May 2003 graduate
  - Wekerle, John Echoes of two wars: a memoir, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 2004
  - Bengal, Christopher Just like God, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    May 2004 graduate
  - Corbett, Keith Preparing students for the future by teaching the business context, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Driscoll, Erin Discussion on the physical, social and emotional effects of the technological expansion, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Flynn, Carrie Adolescence: dificult family situations and their academic repercussions, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Foster, Kerin Sarah's best friend, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Fry, Genevieve Summer vacation, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Giordano, Aprile M. Surviving adolescents, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    December 2004 graduate
  - Graffeo, Janine An editor's point of view: a look into the history of news editing and its applications, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - McGee, Megan Eavesdropping, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Shutak, Melissa Teaching reading through method and material frameworks in elemantary school, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- 2005
  - Ammirata, Jessica The fang collection, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    May 2005 graduate
  - Borchetta, Jessica Suit of swords, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Currier, Amanda Starbucks to Seattle: skydiving to freedom, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Gilmore, Joan The earth is round: we will meet again, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Guillette, Bryan Back to this life, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Holm, Michael The world or not and other short stories, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    August 2005 graduate
  - Killarney, Ashley The me compilation, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - McDonald, Lindsey Creating Lindsay K, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - McNamara, Laura The meaning of life in plaster and other short stories, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Mercede, Darlene It is never too late to change, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Mulvey, Courtney A semester; a broad: sotries of my semester abroad, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Nelson, Michelle Housing and residence life: as told by those in the field, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Norlander, Matthew Collegiate athletics: an examination of how student-athletes are treated and how the NCAA funds intercollegiate sports at all levels, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Patton, Erica Monotheism in America: the voices, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Phillips, Heather Senior thesis memoir, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Pontolilo, Brian Ordinary People: a series of profiles, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Siepmann, Debra Tangles, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- 2006
  - Arce, Vanessa Stories of the unknown, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    May 2006 graduate
  - Arciola, Dawn The Diary of Isabelle, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Brennan, Daniel Contrapasso, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Bruton, Jennifer Addressing diversity to yourng children through literature, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Dioguardi, Theresa Life's unanswered questions, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - DiSilvestro, Diana Spooky New England, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Dorcey, Eileen Scars, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Fonseca, Marco Fear and loathing in Fairfield County, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Glad, Joseph Zuccan Tales, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Glasgow, Stephanie Splash time: a series of three short stories based on true dramatic events, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Goodman, Talya Granuaile: a pirate tale, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Hamilton, Ashley, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Kane, Melanie We are all a work in progress, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Karjanis, Jessica Dreams of Verona, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Kiviniemi, Hanna The losers who win, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Krupinsky, Dana The making of Fairfield County Fare, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Kuzbel, Kayla Behind the curtain: As You Like It 2006 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Marshall, Luke Lost and found in the land of my fathers: a travelogue, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - McDaniel, Paul The Next Supper, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Raymond, Katie Behind the razor wire: my visits with Pamela Smart and the Bedford Hills correctional facility, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Sar, Virya White flower, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- 2007
  - Albohn, Kevin Tattoos and their significance in the world, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    May 2007 graduate
  - Christopher, Ashley Our stories a family history, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Davenport, Suzanne Not my brothers keeper, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    December 2007 graduate
  - English, James Degrees of happiness, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Ferry, Mark J Stuck in neutral, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Garber, Sarah The tragic hero who suffered with a smile, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Gerhard, Zakariaz Hunting dragons, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Isaac, Laura Generation last, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Maher, Kelly The microcosm of newspapers, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - McGuire, Grant Ahitory of DreamWorks/SKG, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Nielsen, Kara Sanity and happiness: can they coexist, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Slie Shelby My guidge to teaching writing, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Weiss, Leia Walker's moon, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Wilkes, Marilyn Pulbic relations and six life lessons, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Zeller, Maura The children left behind, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- 2008
  - Coutu, Brian Incendia's ashes, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    December 2008 graduate
  - Delille, Christopher A brief history of WXCI, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Hohenshelt, Stewart Alan Behind closed doors, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Miller, Marie Pedagogy for teaching writing, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Ready, John Marketing Communications Implementation on the Valley Uniteed Way Community Campaign, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Richards, Rebecca Five of Connecticut's finest: suprising close to home, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Rizzi, Peter And they called him Johnny, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Stone, Danielle Jell-o molds and nacho platters: decade defining dishes in American-home entertaining from the 1950's-1990's, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Stupple, Nam Sung Hallo! Welcome in Egypt, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Wittestein, Max "Is that guy a student here?": a profile of Jerome Bibuld, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- 2009
  - Andreoli, Kristen You are served, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    May 2009 graduate
  - Benedict, Joseph Down city, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Bowles, Phil A world away: inside the world of warcraft, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    December 2009 graduate
  - Burks, Jennifer The shattered nuclear family, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Cockburn, Michael Reflections of existence, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Doolittle, Kara Going up?, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Gray, Matthew What now Pops?, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Kara, Jake The fairest of the seasons, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - McNulty-DeNuzio, Kevin The symphony of arches, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Neeves, Nicholas The variant, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Reichard, Jeffrey The lost accounts of Dr. Watson, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Salha, Fernanda Between us, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Sousa, Suzana Social media and its influence in politics, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Strout, David The mineworker, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Ungar, Daniel Sticks and stones, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Weinkauf, Kristin Hearts or tails, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- 2010
  - Bartenstein, Kimberly Going green: who's committee and who's faking their commitment?, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    May 2010 graduate
  - Black, Kai-Lin Blended families: what is the glue that holds them together?, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Durkin, Joshua Khalid Shikh Mohammed and the developments of the 9/11 trial, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Esposito, Dena Fostering critical thinking through critical pedagogy in the high school english classroom, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Goldman, Jonathan Desert Dust, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Iacovacci, Lauren Biodegradable products are the future, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Jacob, Thomas Raz, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Mancini, Lisa Father Absence and its effects on daughers, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Marden, Nancy Exposing the cyberbully, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Monda, Erin Only the wounded, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Noeding, Dane The effects of the current recession on crime in America, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Rosso, Joe Live on, the champion, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Tucker, Jesse Arlin's watch, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Weinstein, Ilyse Igniting a passion for poetry in elementary school, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Whitlock, Meghan The importance of informal writing in the classroom: a guide to formal writing, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- 2010 (Dec. grads)
  - Barrett, Robert Mr. Black, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Glazer, Leah Muerte Circo, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Glykokokalos, Steve Fanatics and Their Obsessions, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Jacocks, Catherine Alix Girls and Horses, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Koukides, Eleni Food Allergies: An Everyday Battle, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - LeConche, Lindsey Hang Up Your Cleats, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Lowe, James One and Done, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Miller, Gregory The Influence of Big Banks in Congress, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Perreten, Kayleigh Normalcy; A collection of short stories, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Polito, Matthew Cargo, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Pryor-Bennett, Will Wander Yonder, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Simas, Rebecca Day Dreamer, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Storez, Raymond Connecticut Hardcore: A Journalistic Expose on Punk and Hardcore And DIY Culture in Connecticut, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- 2011
  - Arrowitz, Jason Truth and Darkness, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    May 2011 graduate
  - Beyer, James Under the Rock, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Burgess, Monica At War, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Carr, Khaliah The Connections in Relationships, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Donofrio, Allison Digging Up the Past, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Farrell, John The Costume Party, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Honore, Michael Bad Superheroes, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Kaimer, Katryna M. Taking the Scenic Route, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Kass, Alison The 20th Century of American Fashion: 1900-2000, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Martin, Norvell N. BEFORE THE SNAP, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Mauermann, Peter Back To Basics, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Mrotek, Helen (Kate) From Darkness to Light: a memoir on being bipolar, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Parzuchowski, Michelle A Chain of Events, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Pickle, Kathy Losing Enchanton, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Rippollone, Mike When The Balloon Goes Up, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Seedorff, Sofie Travels with Mike: In Search of the World, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Terjek, Alison The Parting of the Sea, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Buonadonna, Anthony Crossover, A Graphic Novel, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    December 2011 graduate
  - Clarke, Amanda Cannibal Love, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Gillen, Justin Harmonious Prosperity: Examples of Instrumental and Musical Benefits, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Grant, Jason This Will be the Life of Me, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Harris, Nicole The Benefits of Writing through Art in the Classroom, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Lawless, Laurie An Honest Look at Pit Bulls, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Pittman, Caressa Has the Portrayal of Women in the Media Changed Enough Since the 1950's?, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Sincerbeaux, Caitlyn Understanding Ethics in Public Relations: Essentials for a Graduating Public Relations Majors, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Carneglia, Kevin RE: GEN, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    May 2012 graduate
  - Connor, Brian P. Pieces of Montes, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Lopes, Hobson The World of Beer League Softball: Why We Play, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Moore, Preston PostOpFitness.com: A Comprehensive Business Plan for an Internet Content Publishing and Marketing Website, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Prezelski, Samuel Martin A Story About A Guy: The Continuing Adventures Of A Man Who Adventures, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Queiroz, Linda Anne Abused Women - Why Do They Stay?, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Roberts, Denise L. Proposal for New Learning Program: The Write Road, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Robinson, Gary Division III Athletics; Keeping the Student in Student-Athlete, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Roland, Keith Song for Sunrise, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Serrano, Zulai Carol's Hourglass, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Spada, Shannon Life or Death, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Troiano, Danielle Alienation, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Westerholm, Russell The Last Three Outs; When closers choke, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 51)